Mohammed Ramadan Zaki

Cairo, Egypt | +201098084247 | mohmdramadn97@gmail.com | <u>Linkedin</u> | <u>Github</u> | English proficiency (B2C)

OBJECTIVE

Flutter developer with 2 years of experience with creating elegant solutions in least amount of time. Contributed to e-commerce apps like (8 orders on <u>Google play</u> and <u>App Store</u>, - Trenjh on <u>Google play</u>), Ishop salesmen app on <u>Google play</u> and a social media platform for LifeBonders. Passionate about best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of mobile applications.

EXPERIENCE

Flutter Developer

Jan 2022 – Present

AccFlex ERP CO - Cairo, Egypt

- Responsible for maintaining existing e-commerce applications and enhancing its performance.
- Built Flavors (build types on android and schemas on IOS) for different build production environments.
- Responsible for developing cross-platform applications for salesmen where applications are connected to AccFlex's ERP system.
- Boosted user experience by 60% by enhancing UI design for existing and new applications (ex. 8orders).
- Work as part of cross-functional, agile project teams to ensure quality is driven into the heart of the development process.
- High response to customer issues which increased customer satisfaction by 35% about our mobile products.
- Prototyped a new application for salesmen with new UI and features.

Flutter Developer

Mar 2021 – Mar 2022

<u>LifeBonder CO</u> – Copenhagen, Denmark (Part time - Remotely)

- Built LifeBonder's social media mobile application.
- Lead a small team of 2 members on the time frame of the project and how much time each task will take.

SKILLS

- Provider and Bloc for state management.
- Good knowledge with RESTful APIs, OpenAPI and Swagger.
- Experience with get_it dependency injection.
- Experience with offline storage, such as Hive, sqlflite.
- Built Reusable components of flutter widgets.
- Hands on architecture patterns like Singleton, MVVM.
- Stick to DRY, KISS and YAGNI clean code principles.
- Good understanding of Clean code, SOLID and OOP design principles.
- Managing localization for i10n.
- Knowledge of CI/CD tools like Azure devops pipelines.
- Design UI for different screen sizes.
- Proficient understanding of code versioning tools, such as Git.
- Debugging on customers issues and resolving them.
- Run test cases written by QA engineers.
- Good command of writing unit tests.
- Understanding of Reactive Programming.
- Good problem solving skills.
- Ability to understand and translate business requirements into technical features.
- Good knowledge of Python, MySQL, NoSQL(Firebase).
- Familiarity with modern authorization mechanisms, such as JSON Web Token.
- Good experience in integrating with the native hardware components as well as different 3rd party SDKs and libraries.
- Excellent knowledge in Android Studio and Xcode.
- Good analytical skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology

Cape Breton University Sept 2015 - July 2019

Graduation project: (Android Application for online donations - Grade: A+)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart Flutter Certificate (July 2019-October 2019)
- Android Developer Track Android Certificate(February 2018-April 2018)
- Data Analysis Professional Certificate link (April 2021-June 2021)